Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to another great podcast here at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的另一期精彩播客。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是 Erika。
And today we're going to be bringing you bad news.
今天我们要给大家带来坏消息。
That's right.
没错。
Actually, what we're really going to be bringing you is language to talk about bad news.
实际上，我们真正要带来的是谈论坏消息的语言。
Exactly.
正是。
So maybe you have to give bad news to your boss, to your parents, I don't know, somebody,
所以，也许你需要向老板、父母或某人传达坏消息，
and we're going to be teaching you how to do this in English.
我们将教你如何用英语做到这一点。
Well, obviously, it's always difficult to tell somebody bad news, but in your second
嗯，显然，告诉别人坏消息总是很难，但用你的第二语言，
language, it's even harder.
就更难了。
So we're going to try and help you today with some great phrases and vocabulary items.
所以今天我们会用一些很棒的短语和词汇来帮助你。
We're not going to preview anything today.
我们今天不会做任何预览。
Let's go directly to our dialogue where we will be in a company and one of the employees
我们直接进入对话，场景是在一家公司，其中一名员工
is going to be giving bad news to his boss.
将向他的老板传达坏消息。
So let's listen.
那么，让我们来听一听。
Now that we've been over the gory details of our disastrous first quarter, Ed, give
既然我们已经详细了解了第一季度的惨痛细节，Ed，给
us some good news.
我们一些好消息吧。
How are things looking for us in terms of sales this month?
这个月我们的销售情况如何？
Well, would you like the bad news first or the really bad news?
嗯，您想先听坏消息还是真正的坏消息？
What?
什么？
Ed, don't tell me you only have bad news.
Ed，别告诉我你只有坏消息。
Well, sir, our sales have dropped, no plunged, 50% in the past month alone.
嗯，先生，我们的销售额下降了，不，是暴跌了，仅上个月就下降了 50%。
We are currently overstocked and overstaffed and our profits are falling fast.
我们目前库存积压、人员过剩，利润正在快速下滑。
The market is in recession and we have no way of moving our inventory or getting rid
市场处于衰退期，我们无法清空库存或裁减
of our staff.
员工。
If we consider redundancies, it costs us a fortune because of the new regulations governing
如果我们考虑裁员，由于新的
compensation packages.
补偿方案规定，这会花费我们一大笔钱。
It's a real mess.
真是一团糟。
You're crying out loud.
你真是的。
How fast are we losing money?
我们亏钱的速度有多快？
How can I put this?
我该怎么说呢？
Let's just say that at this pace, we will be filing for Chapter 11 in less than three
这么说吧，按照这个速度，我们将在不到三个月内申请
months.
破产保护。
What?
什么？
Jeez, how could this have happened?
天哪，这怎么可能发生？
So what's the bad news?
那坏消息是什么？
Oh, that's the really bad news.
哦，那才是真正的坏消息。
Our supplier suffered QC problems and, well, half of our production is faulty.
我们的供应商出现了质量控制问题，而且，我们一半的产品都有缺陷。
We're going to have to recall all items sold in the last quarter and the worst part, we're
我们必须召回上个季度售出的所有产品，最糟糕的是，我们
going to have to shoulder this cost.
得承担这笔费用。
Are you joking?
你在开玩笑吗？
Get the supplier on the line now.
马上把供应商给我叫来。
They have to assume the cost of this mess.
他们必须承担这烂摊子的费用。
We tried that, sir.
我们试过了，先生。
The factory has gone under and the owner apparently has fled the country.
工厂已经倒闭了，老板显然已经逃到国外了。
Oh, we're doomed.
哦，我们完蛋了。
There's some really good news, though.
不过，也有一些真正的好消息。
Really?
真的吗？
What?
什么？
I got offered a new job.
我找到了一份新工作。
All right, it sounds like a pretty tough time for this company, doesn't it?
好吧，听起来这家公司处境相当艰难，是吧？
But good news for the employee.
但对员工来说是好消息。
He won't be jobless.
他不会失业。
Well, I guess he knows when to get out.
嗯，我想他知道什么时候该脱身。
But why don't we take a look at some of the language now in Language Takeaway.
不过，我们现在来看看“语言要点”中的一些语言点。
So in Language Takeaway today, we have five vocabulary items and, well, let's start with
在今天的“语言要点”中，我们有五个词汇项目，嗯，让我们从
the first one.
第一个开始。
All right, so the boss, he's talking about the gory details of our disastrous first quarter.
好的，老板在谈论“我们灾难性第一季度的血淋淋细节”。
So let's look at the phrase gory details.
那么，我们来看看“血淋淋的细节”这个短语。
All right, so gory details.
好的，“血淋淋的细节”。
Gory details.
“血淋淋的细节”。
This sounds kind of strange, gory details.
这听起来有点奇怪，“血淋淋的细节”。
It seems very scary.
看起来非常吓人。
Well, the word gory comes from gore, like blood and guts, right?
嗯，“gory”这个词来自“gore”，意思是血和内脏，对吧？
Exactly.
正是。
That's why it sounds a little bit scary to me.
这就是为什么它让我觉得有点吓人。
So gory details mean all the little details of a negative or shocking or bad situation.
所以“血淋淋的细节”指的是一个负面、令人震惊或糟糕情况的所有微小细节。
Okay, so the gory details of the meeting, so all the nasty negative stuff.
好的，比如会议的“血淋淋的细节”，就是所有令人不快的负面内容。
Or the gory detail, or you could say the newspaper reported all the gory details of the murder.
或者“血淋淋的细节”，你也可以说报纸报道了谋杀案的所有血淋淋细节。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So gory details.
所以是“血淋淋的细节”。
So the employee was talking about how bad the company was doing and he mentioned this
那么，员工在谈论公司状况有多糟糕时，提到了
word redundancies.
“裁员”这个词。
Redundancies.
“裁员”。
They are considering redundancies.
他们在考虑裁员。
Okay, so redundancies, again, it's based on the word to be redundant.
好的，“redundancies”这个词，它基于“redundant”这个词。
All right, and that means?
好的，那是什么意思？
To not be needed anymore.
不再被需要了。
Okay, so redundancies are basically firing people.
好的，所以“redundancies”基本上就是解雇员工。
It's well, laying people off, people that you don't need anymore.
嗯，是裁员，解雇那些你不再需要的人。
They are redundancies.
他们就是被裁的人。
All right, so this is actually a British term, redundancies, to become redundant, because
好的，这实际上是一个英式术语，“redundancies”，“to become redundant”，因为
in American English, you would just say layoffs.
在美式英语中，你只会说“layoffs”。
Yep.
是的。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
All right, so moving on.
好的，我们继续。
They were talking about redundancies and maybe they should or shouldn't lay some people off,
他们在谈论裁员，也许他们应该或不应该解雇一些人，
but one of the problems were the regulations governing compensation packages.
但问题之一是“管理补偿方案的规定”。
Okay, so regulations governing compensation packages.
好的，“管理补偿方案的规定”。
Regulations governing something.
“管理某事物的规定”。
So we have a noun governing noun.
所以这是一个名词修饰名词的结构。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
All right, so I think it would help us to understand this a little better if we listen
好的，我想如果我们听一些这种“名词修饰名词”结构的例子，
to some examples of this pattern, noun governing noun.
会帮助我们更好地理解。
Example one.
例子一。
I don't agree with the regulations governing income taxes.
我不同意管理所得税的规定。
People shouldn't have to give away their hard-earned money.
人们不应该交出他们辛苦赚来的钱。
Example two.
例子二。
We need to protect the environment.
我们需要保护环境。
Therefore, there will be new policies governing corporate levels of pollution starting next
因此，从下个月开始，将会有新的政策来管理企业的污染水平。
month.
Example three.
例子三。
The lack of regulations governing city transportation has led to many traffic accidents.
缺乏管理城市交通的规定导致了许多交通事故。
Okay, great examples.
好的，很好的例子。
And well, before we move on, this compensation packages, I guess it's all the things that
嗯，在我们继续之前，这个“补偿方案”，我猜是公司解雇你时
the company gives you when they lay you off, right?
给你的所有东西，对吧？
Right, maybe a certain portion of your retirement benefits or...
对，可能是你退休福利的一部分，或者...
Like a month's pay, etc.
比如一个月的工资等等。
Okay, compensation packages.
好的，“补偿方案”。
All right, so moving on to our next item on Language Takeaway, we have to shoulder the
好的，那么继续我们“语言要点”的下一个项目，我们有“承担
cost.
费用”。
To shoulder the cost.
“承担费用”。
All right, so if I shoulder something...
好的，如果我“shoulder”某件事...
You have to carry it.
你必须承担它。
I carry it.
我承担它。
Yeah, that's a good one.
是的，这个说法很好。
So basically, it's the same as the shoulder, your body.
所以基本上，它和“肩膀”这个身体部位是一样的。
So you carry this cost or you carry this responsibility.
所以你承担这笔费用或承担这个责任。
So you might also hear shoulder the burden.
所以你也可能听到“承担重担”。
To shoulder the burden.
“承担重担”。
So it just means to carry the responsibility.
所以它只是意味着承担责任。
Okay, to share it.
好的，分担责任。
Yeah.
是的。
All right, interesting.
好的，有意思。
And we have one more word on Language Takeaway.
在“语言要点”中我们还有一个词。
And the factory has gone under.
工厂已经倒闭了。
To go under.
“倒闭”。
All right, to go under.
好的，“倒闭”。
When something goes under, a company goes under, it goes bankrupt.
当某事物“倒闭”时，一家公司“倒闭”，它就破产了。
It goes bankrupt.
它破产了。
So it's not working anymore.
所以它不再运作了。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so to go under.
好的，所以是“倒闭”。
Great vocabulary items here on Language Takeaway today.
今天“语言要点”中的词汇项目很棒。
It's time for us to move on to the next segment of our show where we're going to look at some
是时候进入我们节目的下一个环节了，我们将看看一些
phrases.
短语。
So let's start now with Fluency Builder.
那么，我们现在开始“流利度构建”环节。
Fluency Builder.
“流利度构建”。
All right, so we've got some phrases that you can use when somebody is going to tell
好的，我们有一些短语，你可以用在当别人要告诉你
you some bad news, but also some phrases you can use to deliver bad news.
一些坏消息时，也有一些短语可以用来传达坏消息。
All right, so let's start with our first phrase.
好的，让我们从第一个短语开始。
So the boss is getting ready to prepare for this bad news and he says, lay it on me.
老板准备好接受这个坏消息，他说，“告诉我吧”。
He's like, okay, lay it on me.
他说，“好吧，告诉我吧”。
Lay it on me.
“告诉我吧”。
So if I say this, lay it on me, I'm just saying, tell me.
所以如果我说这个，“告诉我吧”，我只是在说，“告诉我”。
Exactly.
正是。
So give me the bad news.
所以把坏消息告诉我。
All right, so lay it on me.
好的，所以是“告诉我吧”。
Very informal though.
不过非常非正式。
Yeah, you're right.
是的，你说得对。
It is kind of informal.
这有点非正式。
But our next phrase, the boss is hearing about all this bad news and he says, for crying
但我们的下一个短语，老板在听到所有这些坏消息后说，“真是的”。
out loud.
“真是的”。
For crying out loud.
All right, so this is a very common phrase of frustration.
好的，这是一个非常常见的表达沮丧的短语。
So why don't we listen to some examples to kind of understand how we use this phrase.
那么，我们为什么不听一些例子来理解如何使用这个短语呢。
Example one.
例子一。
For crying out loud, when I tell you to have the report done by Wednesday, that means I
真是的，我告诉你星期三之前把报告完成，那意味着我
expect it to be on my desk by the end of the day.
希望它在当天结束时出现在我的桌子上。
Example two.
例子二。
We've got to figure out a new marketing strategy for crying out loud.
真是的，我们得想出一个新的营销策略。
Example three.
例子三。
For crying out loud, you just got your driving license and you already got in an accident.
真是的，你刚拿到驾照就出事故了。
So it kind of reminds me of, oh my God.
这让我想起，“哦，我的天哪”。
So you're frustrated, you're just saying this phrase as, oh my God, or something like this.
所以你感到沮丧，你只是说这个短语，就像“哦，我的天哪”或类似的东西。
Yeah, it's like, oh, this is so annoying.
是的，就像“哦，这太烦人了”。
Exactly.
正是。
For crying out loud.
“真是的”。
Yep.
是的。
All right, moving on to our third phrase.
好的，继续我们的第三个短语。
How can I put this?
“我该怎么说呢？”
So the boss asked him a direct question and he said, well, how can I put this?
老板直接问了他一个问题，他说，“嗯，我该怎么说呢？”
So we use this phrase, we want to say something maybe a little bit more indirectly.
所以我们用这个短语，当我们想说一些可能有点间接的话时。
Right, so you're looking for words of how you can make it softer or more polite.
对，所以你在寻找如何让它更柔和或更礼貌的措辞。
Maybe the truth or what you're about to say is a little bit strong, so you want to soften
也许你要说的真相有点强烈，所以你想让它
it up a bit.
缓和一点。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, so you say, how can I put this?
好的，所以你说，“我该怎么说呢？”
But then you have to complement it with, let's just say that.
但然后你必须补充说，“这么说吧”。
Let's just say that.
“这么说吧”。
So how do we use this phrase?
那么我们如何使用这个短语呢？
So for example, somebody asks me, well, what do you mean?
例如，有人问我，“嗯，你什么意思？”
Why can't you come on vacation with us?
“你为什么不能和我们一起去度假？”
And I would say, how can I put this?
我会说，“我该怎么说呢？”
Let's just say that in nine months you will hear the pitter patter of little feet.
“这么说吧，九个月后你会听到小脚丫啪嗒啪嗒的声音。”
Okay, so your girlfriend's pregnant.
好的，所以你女朋友怀孕了。
Exactly.
正是。
So you're not saying, my girlfriend is pregnant.
所以你没有直接说，“我女朋友怀孕了”。
You're giving like a metaphor.
你给了一个比喻。
A metaphor of what's going on, but you don't want to say it directly.
一个关于正在发生的事情的比喻，但你不想直接说出来。
Yeah.
是的。
So for example, I might say, let's just say that Michael isn't doing a great job.
例如，我可能会说，“这么说吧，Michael 做得不太好。”
All right.
好的。
So maybe there are very strong reasons or he's doing very, very poorly.
所以也许有非常强烈的原因，或者他做得非常非常差。
Right.
对。
But I'm just sort of not saying it exactly directly that he's doing bad.
但我只是没有直接说他做得不好。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So it's a phrase that you can actually use a lot and to be a little bit more polite or
所以这是一个你可以经常使用的短语，用来更礼貌一点，或者
a little bit more indirect when you're giving somebody some bad news.
在给别人坏消息时更委婉一点。
Exactly.
没错。
So we have two nice sort of complimenting phrases for delivering bad news and why don't
所以我们有两个很好的、用来传达坏消息的委婉表达，不如
we hear them one more time in the dialogue.
我们再听一遍对话中的这些表达。
Now that we've been over the gory details of our disastrous first quarter, Ed, give
既然我们已经讲完了我们灾难性第一季度的糟糕细节，埃德，给
us some good news.
我们一些好消息吧。
How are things looking for us in terms of sales this month?
我们这个月的销售情况怎么样？
Well, would you like the bad news first or the really bad news?
嗯，你想先听坏消息还是特别坏的消息？
What?
什么？
Don't tell me you only have bad news.
别告诉我你只有坏消息。
Well, sir, our sales have dropped.
嗯，先生，我们的销售额下降了。
No plunged 50% in the past month alone.
不，是上个月就暴跌了50%。
We are currently overstocked and overstaffed and our profits are falling fast.
我们目前库存积压、人员过剩，利润正在快速下滑。
The market is in recession and we have no way of moving our inventory or getting rid
市场处于衰退期，我们没有办法清空库存或解雇
of our staff.
员工。
If we consider redundancies, it costs us a fortune because of the new regulations governing
如果我们考虑裁员，由于新的补偿方案
compensation packages.
规定，这会花费一大笔钱。
It's a real mess.
真是一团糟。
You're coming out loud.
你说话声音很大。
How fast are we losing money?
我们亏损的速度有多快？
How can I put this?
我该怎么说呢？
Let's just say that at this pace, we will be filing for Chapter 11 in less than three
这么说吧，按照这个速度，我们将在不到三个月内申请
months.
第11章破产。
What?
什么？
Jeez, how could this have happened?
天哪，这怎么会发生？
So what's the bad news?
那坏消息是什么？
Oh, that's the really bad news.
哦，那就是特别坏的消息。
Our suppliers suffered QC problems and well, half of our production is faulty.
我们的供应商出现了质量控制问题，而且，我们一半的产品有缺陷。
We're going to have to recall all items sold in the last quarter and the worst part, we're
我们必须召回上个季度售出的所有商品，最糟糕的是，我们
going to have to shoulder this cost.
得承担这笔费用。
Are you joking?
你在开玩笑吗？
Get the supplier on the line now.
现在就把供应商给我叫到电话上来。
They have to assume the cost of this mess.
他们必须承担这团乱账的费用。
We tried that, sir.
我们试过了，先生。
The factory has gone under and the owner apparently has fled the country.
工厂已经倒闭了，老板显然已经逃到国外了。
We're doomed.
我们完蛋了。
There's some really good news though.
不过还是有一些真正的好消息。
Really?
真的吗？
What?
什么？
I got offered a new job.
我找到了一份新工作。
All right, great.
好吧，太好了。
So this topic of filing for Chapter 11 is actually very recent, very common now because
所以这个申请第11章破产的话题实际上非常新，现在很常见，因为
recently one of the biggest companies filed for Chapter 11 in the US.
最近美国一家最大的公司申请了第11章破产。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
But I often get confused by the phrase to file for Chapter 11 versus to file for Chapter
但我经常搞混“申请第11章破产”和“申请第13章破产”
13.
这两个短语。
All right, so in the United States, the bankruptcy law has different chapters or different sections,
好的，在美国，破产法有不同的章节或不同的部分，
right?
对吧？
And Chapter 11 is basically for companies that run out of money, that go bankrupt, so
第11章基本上适用于那些资金耗尽、破产的公司，所以
they have to declare themselves in bankruptcy and so they file for Chapter 11.
它们必须宣布破产，然后申请第11章。
But what about Chapter 13?
那第13章呢？
Chapter 13 is for people.
第13章适用于个人。
So people who have large debts, maybe with the car company or the telephone company and
所以那些欠下大笔债务的人，比如欠汽车公司或电话公司的钱，
they can't pay, they file for Chapter 13.
还不起，他们就申请第13章。
They say, hey, I don't have money, I can't pay.
他们会说，嘿，我没钱，我付不起。
So I guess here it's kind of a metaphor again.
所以我猜这里又是一个比喻。
This phrase to file for Chapter 11 or Chapter 13 meaning bankruptcy.
这个短语“申请第11章或第13章破产”意思是破产。
And people will say personally that they're filing for Chapter 11.
人们也会在个人层面上说他们正在申请第11章破产。
Exactly.
没错。
Right, so this is an interesting situation because if you file for bankruptcy in some
对，所以这是一个有趣的情况，因为如果你在某些国家申请破产，
countries, you can go to jail.
你可能会坐牢。
I read recently about this happening in Dubai actually.
我最近读到迪拜就发生过这种事。
Exactly.
没错。
So there is prison for debts.
所以那里有债务监禁。
In the US, you don't go to prison for debts.
在美国，你不会因为债务而坐牢。
But what about in your country's listeners?
但你们国家的听众呢？
What happens when you go into debt in your country?
在你们国家，欠债会怎么样？
Or what happens when a company goes into bankruptcy?
或者公司破产会怎么样？
Let us know.
告诉我们吧。
Come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
来我们的网站，EnglishPod.com。
Leave your questions and comments.
留下你的问题和评论。
And of course, Erica and I are always there to help you out.
当然，艾丽卡和我随时都在那里帮助你。
Thanks for downloading you guys and until next time, goodbye.
感谢你们的下载，下次见，再见。
Bye.
再见。
Bye-bye.
拜拜。